As belles, they were ding-dongs... they enlisted, and were rotten to the corps... and when
things got hotter... they went to the cooler... now, they're on the loose again!
The Apple Dumpling Gang Rides Again is a comedy, family,
western film directed by Vincent McEveety.
Amos and Theodore, the two bumbling outlaw wannabes from The Apple
Dumpling Gang, are back and trying to make it on their own.
This time, the crazy duo gets involved in an army supply theft case --
and, of course, gets in lots of comic trouble along the way!
Amos Tucker, played by Tim Conway.
Theodore, played by Don Knotts.
Jeff Reed, played by Tim Matheson.
Woolly Bill Hitchcock, played by Kenneth Mars.
Miss Millie Gaskill, played by Elyssa Davalos.
Big Mac, played by Jack Elam.
The Apple Dumpling Gang is a 1975 American
comedy-Western film directed by Norman Tokar.
It follows a slick gambler named Russell Donovan (Bill Bixby) who is duped
into taking care of three orphans who eventually strike gold.
It was produced by Walt Disney Productions.
The film is based on the 1971 novel of the same name by Jack M.
Don Tait wrote the screenplay.
The so-called "Apple Dumpling Gang" are named after their
favorite American dessert treat, the apple dumpling.
It is also known as being the first film to feature the
comedy duo of Don Knotts and Tim Conway.
Buddy Baker composed the music for the film and its sequel, The Apple Dumpling
Gang Rides Again, with Joseph Dubin performing the orchestration.
The song "The Apple Dumpling Gang", as heard in the opening and closing credits, was composed
by Shane Tatum and was performed by Randy Sparks and the Back Porch Majority.
The tone is lighthearted.